Srihari K

srih4ri@gmail.com Github Phone: +91 7204275616

A hacker by nature, worked in two product companies in various stages of product development. Also had short stints of starting up and freelancing.

Experienced in sysadmin roles - deploying, monitoring, intervening during traffic peaks. Proficient in identifying and fixing database bottlenecks in Rails applications.

Used mysql, redis, Rails (2.x and above in production), ElasticSearch, wkhtmltopdf, Capistrano. Also worked with Twitter/Facebook APIs. Familiar with JS frameworks like Backbone JS and React.

Experience

Software Consultant, Big Binary

July 2015 - Present

Various projects for clients, providing expertise in Ruby on Rails and ReactJS. Projects worked on included e-commerce systems, mobile app backends and logistics software built using rails.

Few blog posts on **BigBinary Blog**

Software Architect, Bang The Table.

Jan, 2013 - July 2015

Engagement HQ v1

Version 1 of flagship product of Bang The Table - Now retired.

Enhanced v1 version of Engagement HQ (Rails 2.3.8) with new feature requests. Added bundler, capistrano support enhancing the build and release process of the single tenant app for \sim 200 clients.

Worked with the support team with meeting SLAs.

Peacekeeper HQ

Moderation as a service product from Bang The Table

Added HTTP APIs to Peacekeeper for new EHQ tools.

Engagement HQ v2

EngagmentHQ: Multi-tenanted and enhanced version of Engagement HQ v1.

Software Developer

Developed new features in Engagement HQ, working closely with internal clients.

Wrote and reviewed code with a team, working remotely.

Deployed and setup EHQ on new servers.

Researched and implemented solutions for scaling up in a time critical fashion.

Setup and used monitoring tools including NewRelic.

Served as on call support during critical server issues.

Worked periodically in a support role meeting SLA's.

Senior Software Developer

Worked with a team to deliver milestones in time and iterated in an Agile work environment.

Analyzed cost of development with product managers.

Worked with teams in eliminating unknowns during project planning.

Influenced the technical direction of the product.

Budget Allocator v2:

<u>BudgetAllocator</u>: multi-tenant and enhanced version of Participatory Budget Tool from Bang The Table

Worked in a team of two, with a front end developer.

Upgraded single tenant, Rails 2.x app to multi-tenant, Rails 4 app.

Ensured that the upgrade process was planned and executed keeping the app up and running during the process.

Designed and implemented API's for the ReactJS front end.

Worked closely with product managers in analyzing cost of development for new features.

Actively worked in a team giving feedback and suggestions on new features.

Provided active support for any issues for new clients using the product.

Engineering Lead, Mobizion

May, 2012 - Jan, 2013

Mobify

Mobify is a business intelligence application.

Analyzed market, customer requirements, competitors for building a new product.

Worked with a team and developed the product from scratch.

Manage Team

Ensured quality of code shipped.

Software Engineer, Foradian Technologies

July, 2010 - May, 2012

Fedena

Fedena is a highly successful school ERP developed by Foradian. It is open source and widely used by schools in various parts of the world.

ProjectFedena

Github - Fedena

Worked on the core team of Fedena, developed new features and fixed bugs in the open source code.

Worked on customization of Fedena projects for various clients. Collected, developed and iterated requirements of the clients

Developed Fedena plugin system, utilizing Rails plugin architecture to keep customization for clients DRY.

Sampoorna

Sampoorna is an ERP based on Federa used by Govt of Kerala in over 12,000 schools across Kerala.

Sampoorna

Developed the Rails app for the project.

Served as the technical point of contact from Foradian to Govt. of Kerala.

Deployed and delivered updates of application at Kerala Govt. data center.

Lead a team of engineers to maintain and update the project.

On site assignment for handling peak traffic.

Developed an installer script for the Rails app - packaged the app for Ubuntu in the process.

Fedena SAAS

Ported Fedena into a Multi-Tenant architecture suitable for a SAAS model.

Analyzed automated deployment using Chef.

Setup SAAS Fedena in Amazon EC2.

Built a custom admin interface to Fedena.

Internal Projects

Develop and maintain the software development environment at Foradian.

Conducted sessions on development best practices.
Setup and customized Redmine, Bigtuna (CI) for internal usage.
Setup an application to automate and track code delivery to various clients.

Others

Worked with debian-ruby team to package Ruby Gems for Debian as a part of Diaspora project.

Education

Btech - Electronics and Communication, Lal Bahadur Sasthri College of Engineering.

July, 2010

Fiddled with python, Matlab and php. Formed the first Free Software Users Group of college with friends.

Occasional Freelance web development projects.